One.
Satu.
ARCHAEOLOGICAL EVIDENCE SUGGESTS THE OLDEST BOARD GAMES…
BUKTI ARKEOLOGIS MENUNJUKKAN PERMAINAN PAPAN TERTUA…
Two.
Dua.
…DATE BACK MORE THAN 1,000 YEARS BEFORE CHRIST
…BERUSIA LEBIH DARI 1.000 TAHUN SM
Three.
Tiga.
SOME BELIEVED THEY WERE USED…
KONON ITU DIGUNAKAN…
Four.
Empat.
…AS TALISMAN ENABLING PASSAGE TO THE AFTERLIFE
…SEBAGAI AZIMAT PELINDUNG KE AKHIRAT
Five.
Lima.
BE 2498 AD 1955
2498 TAHUN BUDDHA 1955 MASEHI
Seven.
Tujuh.
Eight.
Delapan.
Nine.
Sembilan.
Ten.
Sepuluh.
Novice…
Nak…
I'm coming for you.
aku datang.
You're in the ordination hall, aren't you?
Kau ada di aula pentahbisan, 'kan?
Novice,
Nak,
come on out.
keluarlah.
You're the last one left.
Kau yang terakhir.
Regardless…
Bagaimanapun juga…
you're gonna fucking die anyway.
kau akan tetap mati.
Mom… No.
Ibu… Jangan.
It's all right, novice.
Tidak apa-apa, Nak.
Just hang on a bit longer.
Bertahanlah sebentar.
No.
Jangan.
It's almost over.
Sebentar lagi selesai.
PRESENT DAY
MASA KINI
You make such stupid moves.
Langkahmu payah.
How are we gonna win?
Bagaimana kita menang?
We've been playing for three days.
Kita sudah bermain selama tiga hari.
It's expensive, and the game's freaking hard.
Permainan ini mahal dan sangat sulit.
You two, stop yapping.
Jangan banyak bicara.
Look, we're at the final boss.
Lihat, kita melawan bos terakhir.
I believe in you.
Aku memercayaimu.
Go for it.
Maju.
You've got this.
Kau pasti bisa.
Make it good, Jord.
Hajar dia, Jord.
Please. Make us win, win, win.
Aku mohon. Bantu kami menang.
-Win! Win! Win!
- Menang!
Did we do it?
Apa kita menang?
-Sure. -For real?
- Tentu saja. - Sungguh?
Way the hell over there.
Jauh sekali di sana.
Your throw was shit.
Lemparanmu tak becus.
Damn it.
Astaga.
-Shit!
- Sial!
Skipping Buddhism class to gamble? What were you thinking?
Bolos kelas agama demi judi? Mau jadi apa kalian?
Ma'am, it's just a board game. We weren't gambling.
Itu hanya permainan papan, Bu. Kami tidak berjudi.
Yeah, there wasn't money involved.
Ya, kami tidak pakai uang.
My shirt's about to rip.
Kemejaku hampir sobek.
And you too.
Kau juga.
Is my Buddhism class that boring?
Apa kelas agamaku begitu membosankan?
-Yes.
- Ya.
Tomorrow, 6:00 a.m. All of you, meet me at school.
Besok, pukul 06.00. Kalian semua temui aku di sekolah.
Tell your parents.
Kabari orang tua.
Get inside.
Masuk.
I'll be docking points from all of you.
Poin kalian akan dikurangi.
All done. Try to avoid getting it dirty.
Selesai. Jaga kebersihannya.
And keep it dry for one to two days.
Jaga tetap kering maksimal dua hari.
Thank you, Doctor.
Terima kasih, Dokter.
You're welcome.
Sama-sama.
Students attend dharma camp tomorrow
BESOK, PARA SISWA ADA KEMAH DARMA
Any questions contact Ms. Au
KONTAK BU AU UNTUK BERTANYA
Damn, I begged my mom to let me sleep over.
Sial, aku sampai memohon kepada Ibu agar bisa menginap.
I wanted to play all day.
Aku mau main seharian.
Au has to show up and ruin it.
Au merusak semuanya.
Just get it over with and hurry back.
Selesaikan saja dengan cepat, lalu kita pulang.
We can play till dawn.
Kita main sampai pagi.
Damn it. Our Four Legends party flopped.
Sial. Pesta Empat Legenda kita gagal.
How can Four Legends only have three people?
Kenapa Empat Legenda hanya bertiga?
A moron like you won't get it.
Orang bodoh tak akan paham.
I'm planning ahead.
Ini rencana jangka panjang.
Since it's only three of us, there are some games we can't play, right?
Karena kita hanya bertiga, pilihan permainan kita terbatas, 'kan?
You're always tripping me up.
Kau selalu membuatku bingung.
Here he is, the key man.
Ini dia, pemain utama.
He will be the keeper of the sacred token,
Dia adalah penjaga lambang suci…
which is the symbol of our gang.
yang merupakan simbol geng kita.
Jord, you ass!
Sialan kau, Jord!
Pick me up at the temple tomorrow night.
Jemput aku di wihara besok malam.
They're taking us there to meditate.
Kami dibawa ke sana untuk meditasi.
So you're gambling at school now?
Kau berjudi di sekolah sekarang?
You're lucky it was Ms. Au.
Beruntung yang lihat Bu Au.
You got off easy.
Hukumanmu tak seberapa.
She called you?
Dia menghubungimu?
Doesn't matter if she did or didn't.
Tidak penting aku tahu dari siapa.
Is it so hard for you to focus on school?
Apa sulit fokus pada pelajaran?
Start acting your age.
Jangan kekanak-kanakan.
You stop acting like Mom.
Jangan berlagak seperti ibuku.
It's only a short detour. Just behind the market.
Hanya melipir sebentar. Pas di belakang pasar.
Drop me off first, my mom's gonna freak out.
Antar aku dulu, nanti ibuku marah.
Don't hit me while I'm driving. We'll crash.
Jangan pukul aku saat bawa motor, bisa celaka.
Jord, the cops are behind us.
Jord, polisi di belakang.
Sarge, take his keys.
Sersan, ambil kuncinya.
You again, huh?
Kau lagi, ya?
Arms out.
Tangan ke atas.
What else are you gonna check, Sarge? My piss?
Memeriksa apa, Pak? Kelaminku?
Watch that filthy mouth of yours.
Kendalikan mulut kotormu.
I already threw your brother in jail.
Kakakmu sudah di penjara.
You're not far behind.
Kau bisa menyusul.
What?
Apa?
My keys.
Kunciku.
Pay the fine first.
Bayar tilang dulu.
Then you can come get it. Go.
Baru ambil di kantor. Sana.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Jord, you forgot your bag.
Jord, tasmu tertinggal.
Sir, he's just a kid. Why are you so hard on him?
Pak, dia hanya anak-anak. Kenapa begitu keras kepadanya?
Sergeant, you're new here. You don't know anything.
Kau masih baru, Sersan. Tak tahu apa-apa.
That boy's nickname is Cutter Jord.
Anak itu Jord si Penikam.
-You can go now, Duan. -Yes, ma'am.
- Kau bisa kembali, Duan. - Baik, Bu.
Come on.
Ayo.
Follow me.
Ikut aku.
Ton.
Ton.
Ton!
Ton!
Shit.
Sial.
Ton.
Ton.
Didn't you say you weren't into it?
Bukankah kau tak percaya?
Seriously?
Ayolah.
Sit up straight.
Duduk tegak.
Skipping Buddhism class to gamble.
Bolos kelas agama Buddha demi judi.
Be lively, like when you're playing those games.
Semangat, seperti saat kalian bermain.
You don't sleep when you're supposed to.
Saat disuruh tidur malah tidak tidur.
Sit upright.
Duduk tegak.
You'll sit here until you recognize your mistakes.
Duduk di sini sampai kalian sadar kesalahan kalian.
Shit, I've got a cramp!
Sial, kakiku keram!
Are you faking it?
Pura-pura, ya?
Of course not, ma'am. It really hurts.
Tidak, Bu. Sakit sekali.
Come on, sit.
Ayo, duduk.
Scrub it clean.
Gosok sampai bersih.
Stop being so dramatic. Work harder.
Jangan berlebihan. Bekerja yang benar.
Do it properly.
Lakukan yang benar.
If there are more misbehaving kids, I'll have to impose on you again.
Kalau ada yang nakal lagi, aku titip lagi, ya?
Their parents will pick them up in the evening.
Mereka akan dijemput orang tuanya nanti malam.
Just have them wait in front of the ordination hall.
Suruh mereka menunggu di depan aula pentahbisan.
Yes, Venerable Sir.
Baik, Bante.
I'll take my leave. I have an errand to run.
Aku akan pergi. Aku masih ada urusan.
Venerable Sir,
Bante,
do you have a saw at the temple?
ada gergaji di wihara?
What do you need it for?
Untuk apa?
To cut down those trees.
Menebang pepohonan.
We can start with this one here.
Kita bisa mulai dengan yang ini.
If we cut it down, there'll be fewer leaves.
Kalau kita tebang, daunnya akan berkurang.
Problem solved.
Masalah selesai.
I'll get my friends to help.
Aku akan minta bantuan yang lain.
Do you think it's a good idea?
Ide bagus, 'kan?
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Man, I'm exhausted!
Astaga, aku lelah sekali!
One day of this, and I'm wiped.
Baru sehari sudah mau tepar.
No way I'm ordaining when I'm 20.
Mustahil aku ikut pentahbisan nanti.
If she really wants me to, she better buy me a PS5.
Kalau ibuku memaksa, sebaiknya, dia membelikan PS5.
I pity her for having a son like you.
Kasihan ibumu punya anak sepertimu.
If she wants a ticket to heaven, she's gotta make an investment.
Kalau ingin tiket ke surga, dia harus berinvestasi.
What's your deal with my mom?
Apa urusanmu dengan ibuku?
Damn, you keep going there.
Kau selalu membicarakan itu.
Ben, are you sure you told your sister 6:00 p.m.?
Ben, kau bilang pukul 18.00 ke kakakmu, 'kan?
It's nearly 7:00.
Ini pukul 19.00.
You think she forgot?
Apa dia lupa?
Why? You scared?
Kenapa? Kau takut?
Keep acting tough.
Coba saja sok jago.
You guys don't know shit.
Kalian tak tahu apa-apa.
Back in the day, at this temple,
Dulu, di wihara ini,
a woman went crazy.
ada wanita yang jadi gila.
She hanged her son who had ordained as a novice.
Dia menggantung putranya yang ditahbiskan sebagai biksu cilik.
Rumor has it that she…
Kabarnya, saat itu dia…
was possessed.
kerasukan.
Even to this day,
Sampai sekarang,
people say they can hear the novice running back and forth, howling.
kata orang, mereka sering dengar langkah kaki dan jeritan biksu cilik itu.
-Damn it, Priktai!
- Astaga, Priktai!
I saw something run inside, so I went to check it out.
Aku lihat ada yang lari masuk, jadi aku periksa.
The novice.
Biksu cilik itu.
I knew it was real.
Aku tahu dia nyata.
A ghost?
Hantu?
Why you gotta say it?
Kenapa bilang begitu?
Those things aren't real.
Mereka tidak nyata.
Don't be stupid.
Jangan bodoh.
Should we follow her?
Apa kita perlu mengikuti dia?
Why should we?
Kenapa?
Ever watched a horror movie?
Pernah menonton film horor?
Whoever hears a strange noise and follows it always ends up dead.
Siapa pun yang mendengar suara aneh dan mengikutinya akan mati.
And besides,
Lagi pula…
Priktai…
Priktai…
is she even human?
memang dia manusia?
I heard Kay from Room 6 say that
Aku dengar dari Kay, anak Kelas 6,
Priktai died in a car crash last year.
kalau Priktai tewas dalam kecelakaan mobil tahun lalu.
But she doesn't know she's dead.
Tapi dia tak sadar.
Haunting shit.
Mengerikan.
You're making shit up.
Kau hanya mengarang.
That's utter nonsense.
Itu omong kosong.
You think a ghost went to class with us all year?
Apa ada hantu yang sekolah sepanjang tahun?
And got straight "A"s in every subject?
Nilainya juga A dalam semua mapel.
I even copied off of her.
Aku menyontek darinya.
What grade did you get?
Kau dapat apa?
I got a D.
Aku dapat D.
That proves it. Duped by a ghost.
Itu buktinya. Ditipu hantu.
Come help me.
Bantu aku.
Guys, let's leave.
Teman-Teman, kita pergi saja.
Ton, don't chicken out.
Ton, jangan jadi pengecut.
Damn it, Ben. I don't think we should open it.
Astaga, Ben. Ini tidak seharusnya kita buka.
There must be a reason why it's been hidden away.
Pasti ada alasannya ini disembunyikan.
Ton, maybe there's something really cool inside.
Ton, mungkin ada hal keren di dalam sini.
Oh, come on.
Ayolah.
If it sucks, we'll just put it back, that's all.
Kalau tidak seru, tinggal dikembalikan.
It's a board game.
Ini permainan papan.
A 12-sided die with Thai numbers on it.
Dadu 12 sisi dengan angka Thailand.
It's kinda strange.
Ini cukup aneh.
Shit.
Astaga.
It's freaking Dungeons & Dragons.
Ini Dungeons & Dragons.
Hey, let me see!
Hei, coba lihat!
The spaces moved according to the die. Look.
Petaknya bergerak sesuai angka dadu. Lihat.
I got a six, right?
Aku dapat enam, 'kan?
Then it moved six spaces.
Itu maju enam langkah.
I'm guessing that
Tebakanku,
it's a cross-the-finish-line game like Snakes and Ladders.
ini permainan adu cepat ke finis seperti Ular Tangga.
The spaces that move
Petak akan bergerak
are based on our die roll.
berdasarkan hasil lemparan dadu.
Wait, why didn't it move?
Tunggu, kenapa ini tidak bergerak?
Let me try.
Biar aku coba.
I think the game knows…
Tampaknya, permainan tahu…
whose turn it is.
ini giliran siapa.
So then,
Kalau begitu…
since the board has four lanes…
karena ada empat jalur…
Yeah, we need four people to play.
Ya, kita butuh pemain keempat.
Hey. Look at the die.
Hei, lihat dadunya.
Shit. How did the numbers disappear?
Sial. Kenapa angkanya hilang?
What is it now?
Apa lagi ini?
"Fir…"
"So…
"Firs… First…"
So…
"First one has ap…"
Sosok pertama telah…
"First one--"
Sosok pertama…"
You're old as fuck and still can't read.
Sudah tua, tapi tak bisa membaca.
Give it here.
Berikan kepadaku.
Here, Ben.
Ini, Ben.
"First one has appeared…"
"Sosok pertama telah menjelma…"
Why the poetic mood all of a sudden?
Kenapa kau bersenandung?
"A single limb…"
"Satu tungkai…"
Ben.
Ben.
Just read it.
Baca saja.
"First one has appeared. Beware."
"Sosok pertama telah menjelma. Waspadalah.
"Do not linger on earthly matters."
Jangan beri tatapan hampa.
"A single limb leaps from front to back."
Satu tungkai melompat maju mundur dengan cepat.
"Its fangs sink deep in the flesh,
Taringnya menghunjam dalam,
ripping its prey to shreds."
mencabik mangsa hingga lumat."
Shit.
Sial.
When we came in, which way were the statues facing?
Waktu masuk tadi, patungnya menghadap ke mana?
Hey, who's there?!
Hei, siapa di sana?
-Jord, what are you doing? -Don't do it.
- Jord, kau mau apa? - Jangan.
Come out, or else…
Keluar atau…
Freaking hell, Jord. Jord!
Astaga, Jord!
No!
Jangan!
What the hell is that?
Apa itu?
Holy shit.
Ya ampun.
Shit.
Sial.
Windows. Shut the damn windows.
Jendela. Tutup jendelanya.
Shut the windows.
Tutup jendelanya.
Why are you standing there?
Kenapa berdiri di sana?
I'm outta here.
Aku mau keluar.
-I'm outta here! -Ton!
- Aku mau keluar! - Ton!
I told you guys not to go inside the ordination hall.
Aku sudah melarang kalian masuk ke aula pentahbisan.
You're messing with shit you don't understand.
Kalian mengusik sesuatu yang tak kalian pahami!
Shit!
Sial!
Ton!
Ton!
-Ton!
- Ton!
Get up, Ton.
Bangun, Ton!
-Jord, quick! -Jord, hurry up!
- Jord, cepat! - Cepat, Jord!
-Go! Run! -Jord, hurry!
- Ayo! Lari!
Damn it, Ben, easy. I'm wounded.
Hati-hati, Ben. Aku terluka.
Hurry, Jord.
Cepat, Jord.
Hurry!
Cepat!
Go!
Ayo!
Shit, it's coming.
Sial, ia datang.
Go faster.
Lebih cepat.
Get outta here.
Pergi dari sini.
Bell.
Bell.
Get in the truck, hurry.
Naik ke mobil, cepat.
No, how could we?
Tidak, bagaimana bisa?
I just hit someone.
Aku baru menabrak orang.
Trust me, it's not what you think.
Percayalah, itu bukan manusia.
Get in, I'll explain later.
Masuk, nanti aku jelaskan.
Come on, get in the truck.
Ayo, masuk ke mobil.
Get in.
Naik.
What the hell is your sister doing?
Apa yang kakakmu lakukan?
-Bell, go! -It's getting up!
- Bell, jalan! - Ia bangun!
Ben, hang on tight.
Ben, pegangan yang erat.
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Go!
Jalan!
I meant go forward!
Maksudku, maju!
Come on! Go!
Ayo! Jalan!
Would you look at that!
Lihat itu!
A cutting board, huh?
Talenan racik, ya?
You're still young, don't get into drugs.
Masih kecil jangan pakai narkoba.
Just saying.
Hanya mengingatkan.
Kids these days are mean.
Anak-anak sekarang kejam.
What was that thing?
Makhluk apa itu?
A ghost.
Hantu.
It came out of the game.
Itu hantu papan permainan.
"Chronicle of the Occult Affairs."
"Kronik Perkara Gaib.
"Inscription 275:
Prasasti 275.
The Royal Chamberlain found a mysterious board game."
Bendahara Kerajaan menemukan permainan papan misterius.
"A portal between the realms of wandering spirits and humans."
Sebuah portal antara dunia manusia dan arwah-arwah gentayangan.
"It was created by a practitioner of heretical black magic."
Permainan ini diciptakan oleh penganut sihir aliran sesat.
"Thus, the board was sealed away in the Chamber of Sorcery."
Papan ini akhirnya disegel di Ruang Sihir.
"Should anyone make the mistake of starting the game…
Siapa pun yang tanpa sengaja memulai permainan…
it will only end
hanya akan berakhir
when a player reaches the slot at the center of the board."
ketika seorang pemain mencapai petak di tengah papan permainan.
"If no one succeeds before the break of dawn…
Jika tak ada yang berhasil saat fajar tiba…
all shall meet their doom."
semua pemain akan menemui ajalnya."
Everyone, stay calm.
Tenang, Anak-Anak.
It's only 8:00 p.m.
Ini masih pukul 20.00.
We've got lots of time before dawn.
Masih banyak waktu hingga fajar.
Damn it!
Sial!
I should've asked the monk for amulets.
Seharusnya, aku minta azimat pada Bante.
If it's a matter of amulets…
Kalau soal azimat…
I never thought the stuff Mom collected would come to use one day.
Aku tak menduga kalau koleksi Ibu akan berguna.
Can we really depend on these?
Apa kita bisa mengandalkan ini?
We were in the ordination hall, and it still managed to get in.
Tadi kita di aula pentahbisan, tapi makhluk itu tetap bisa masuk.
You know nothing, Priktai.
Kau tak tahu apa-apa, Priktai.
I can tell that Ben's mom's stuff is real.
Koleksi ibu Ben jelas bukan barang sembarangan.
But first…
Sebelum itu…
we need to do it right.
kita harus serius.
Go right.
Ke kanan.
Yeah, right there. There, yes.
Ya, di sana. Di sana, ya.
Fortune Yantra, I'm saved.
Yantra Keberuntungan, aku selamat.
Jord, can you go higher?
Bisa lebih tinggi, Jord?
Everyone, repeat after me.
Semua, ulangi ucapanku.
Namo Buddhaya.
Namo Buddhaya.
-Namo Buddhaya.
- Namo Buddhaya.
Atta hi.
Atta hi.
-Atta hi.
- Atta hi.
Attano natho.
Attano natho.
Wait, that phrase means "The self is one's own refuge."
Tunggu, kalimat itu berarti "diri adalah pelindung bagi diri sendiri".
Really?
Benarkah?
Bell.
Bell.
What?
Apa?
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
You mean, for all of this?
Kau meminta maaf untuk situasi ini?
Forget it.
Lupakan saja.
Just finish the game.
Selesaikan permainannya.
You know, you can go back to college.
Kau tahu, kau bisa melanjutkan kuliah.
I'll be a sophomore soon.
Sebentar lagi, aku kelas dua.
You think you can do it?
Yakin kau mampu?
Then start by washing your own underwear, so girls won't laugh at you.
Belajar cuci pakaian dalam sendiri dulu agar tak ditertawakan para gadis.
Quiet.
Diam.
Know-it-all.
Dasar sok tahu.
I'm gonna roll now.
Aku lempar, ya?
"This demon is wicked, it's so sly."
"Iblis ini licik dan penuh tipu daya.
"Controlling and bending your mind."
Merenggut pikiran dan mengendalikan jiwamu.
"Don't stand in doubt or hide in fear."
Jangan gentar atau bersembunyi tanpa daya.
"If you get possessed…
Begitu kerasukan…
you will become vile and corrupt."
kekejian akan memenuhi jiwamu."
Focus
Fokus.
Ben,
Ben,
your sister…
kakakmu…
Ben, run!
Ben, lari!
Bell?!
Bell?
-Bell, what's wrong? -Bell!
- Ada apa, Bell? - Bell!
Move aside.
Minggir.
Bell.
Bell.
Bell!
Bell!
How does it feel to get stabbed,
Bagaimana rasanya ditikam,
Cutter Jord?
Jord si Penikam?
Ton!
Ton!
Ben.
Ben.
Over here.
Sebelah sini.
I'm outta here!
Aku mau keluar!
-Ton!
- Ton!
-Let me out!
- Keluarkan aku!
Ton!
Ton!
Bell.
Bell.
Ben.
Ben.
Ben, don't be scared.
Ben, jangan takut.
When the game is over,
Begitu permainan berakhir,
we'll be back with Mom, Ben.
kita akan kembali bersama Ibu, Ben.
Ton.
Ton.
Bell, no!
Jangan, Bell!
I'm begging you…
Aku mohon…
leave my sister's body.
keluar dari tubuh kakakku.
Don't take my sister, I'm begging you.
Jangan ambil kakakku, aku mohon.
Leave her body.
Keluarlah dari tubuhnya.
Ben, run.
Ben, lari.
Ben, run!
Ben, lari!
Sorry, Ben.
Maaf, Ben.
I had to do it.
Aku terpaksa.
Ben…
Ben…
I know you're worried about your sister.
Aku tahu kau mencemaskan kakakmu,
But the only way to save her…
tapi dia hanya akan selamat…
is to finish this crazy game.
jika kita menyelesaikan ini.
You want us to continue playing?
Kau mau kita lanjut bermain?
If we don't, we'll die.
Atau kita semua mati.
You really believe everything that damn note says?
Kau percaya semua isi catatan itu?
But Priktai has a point.
Priktai ada benarnya.
I'm not like you guys.
Aku tak seperti kalian.
I'm not as daring.
Aku bukan pemberani.
We're all gonna die anyway.
Akhirnya, kita akan tetap mati.
Wouldn't it be better to just wait for dawn?
Bukankah lebih baik menunggu fajar?
But I can't wait for dawn.
Aku tak bisa menunggu.
Ton…
Ton…
let's just finish the game.
mari selesaikan permainan.
You're really gonna do it?
Kalian sungguh akan bermain?
Then let's show them…
Mari kita tunjukkan kepada mereka…
how badass…
betapa keren…
the Four Legends really are.
Empat Legenda ini.
Let's fuck them up.
Kita hajar mereka.
If the amulets won't work, how can we fight back?
Kalau azimat tak berfungsi, bagaimana kita melawan?
I noticed something when the ghost came of out the game.
Aku menyadari sesuatu saat hantu itu keluar dari permainan.
Normally, we can't touch ghosts, right?
Biasanya, kita tak bisa menyentuh hantu, 'kan?
But remember how the note said
Kalian ingat menurut catatan
this game is a portal between our world and theirs?
permainan ini adalah portal antara dunia kita dan mereka?
That means, by playing the game,
Berarti, dengan bermain,
we're basically opening the portal for them.
kita membuka portal untuk mereka.
So, they can attack us.
Kita bisa diserang.
And vice versa.
Juga sebaliknya.
We can attack them too.
Kita juga bisa menyerang.
Did you get that, Jord?
Kau paham, Jord?
Why'd I even ask? He's totally spaced out.
Percuma bertanya. Dia tak mendengarkan.
Shit.
Astaga.
My brother's gun.
Pistol kakakku.
He hid it before the cops got him.
Dia sembunyikan sebelum tertangkap.
Every time a card pops out, we know the ghost is going to appear.
Kita tahu hantu akan muncul begitu gulungannya keluar.
It's like a hint.
Itu seperti petunjuk.
It comes out after you roll.
Tepat setelah dadu dilempar.
It comes out because Priktai rolls?
Setelah giliran Pritkai?
No.
Bukan.
It comes out because we've finished playing a round.
Gulungan itu keluar setelah kita selesai satu putaran.
Look, the numbers on the die are back.
Lihat, angka di dadu muncul lagi.
And here, they've disappeared for exactly one hour.
Kalau diperhatikan, angka itu hilang selama satu jam.
That means I gotta fight ghosts for an hour?
Aku harus melawan hantu selama satu jam?
Let's do this.
Mari bermain.
Damn it.
Sial.
"Spirits of the deep wild woods
"Roh hutan belantara
dwell within the branches."
bersemayam di dahan.
"The trees themselves will hunt."
Pepohonan pun ikut berburu tanpa ampun.
"Those who grow careless
Bagi siapa saja yang lengah,
may lose their lives."
nyawa taruhannya."
You should have cut down the trees.
Kau seharusnya menebang pohonnya.
Looks like a world-class botanical garden
Ini seperti kebun raya kelas dunia.
Ben!
Ben!
Get…
Lepas…
Get off me!
Lepaskan aku!
Ben!
Ben!
Jord.
Jord.
Shit, Ben. Move.
Sial, Ben. Minggir.
Ben!
Ben!
Move.
Minggir.
You bastard!
Kurang ajar!
Ben, I'm sorry.
Maaf, Ben.
Wait for me, damn it!
Tunggu aku, sialan!
Ben, wait.
Ben, tunggu.
Wait for me.
Tunggu aku.
Ton.
Ton.
Ton, the bullets.
Ton, pelurunya.
Priktai!
Priktai!
Jord.
Jord.
-Ben!
- Ben!
Priktai.
Priktai.
Ton!
Ton!
Ton.
Ton.
God damn it!
Sialan!
Ton!
Ton!
Ton.
Ton.
Damn, Ton.
Astaga, Ton.
Die, you weed!
Mati kalian, gulma!
You're so dead.
Tamatlah kalian.
Son of a bitch!
Bajingan!
Damn, why are there so many incidents tonight?
Kenapa malam ini banyak sekali kecelakaan?
Pao, how are we supposed to know where the gunshots came from?
Pao, bagaimana mencari tahu sumber suara pistol itu?
I think they came from this house.
Sepertinya, dari rumah ini.
We're not gonna make it
Kita tak akan selesai
if we keep fighting like this.
kalau terus melawan begini.
I think we should fight that one.
Tampaknya, kita harus menghabisi yang itu.
Gun.
Pistol.
Your gun!
Pistolmu!
Jord, hurry up.
Cepat, Jord.
I can't hold on much longer.
Aku sudah tak sanggup.
Where did it go?
Ke mana ia?
Shit!
Sial!
Jord, pull it.
Tarik, Jord.
You gotta set it on fire, Ben!
Harus kau sulut dengan api, Ben!
That damn brat.
Bocah sialan.
Brought his friends to a theft, and even hurt his own sister.
Menyeret temannya mencuri sampai melukai kakaknya.
You see what I mean, Suar?
Kau lihat maksudku, Suar?
Don't let his age fool you.
Jangan tertipu usianya.
Are you all right?
Nona, kau baik-baik saja?
If so, I'd like to ask you a few things.
Kalau kau baik-baik saja, tolong jawab pertanyaanku.
What did they do?
Apa yang mereka lakukan?
My little brother brought his friends over.
Adikku membawa teman-temannya.
I don't know what they came for,
Entah mereka mau apa,
but when I resisted, they attacked me.
tapi aku diserang saat melawan.
Can you give a statement at the station?
Bisa buat pernyataan ke kantor?
I'll take you to the hospital after.
Nanti kuantar ke rumah sakit.
Let's go.
Mari.
The suspects are three teenage boys and one teenage girl.
Tersangka tiga remaja putra dan satu remaja putri.
Code 20-1 is responding on site.
Kode 20-1 sudah di TKP.
Dude!
Hei!
You sure you can drive?
Kau yakin bisa mengemudi?
I'll try.
Akan kucoba.
Is it too late to bail?
Tidak bisa mundur, ya?
Let's go to the station.
Mari ke kantor.
Hey!
Hei!
Stop right there!
Berhenti!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
Berhenti atau kutembak!
Hey, stop!
Hei, berhenti!
Stop!
Berhenti!
Floor it!
Injak gas!
Are you okay?
Kau tak apa-apa?
Now that we have a vehicle,
Sekarang, kita punya kendaraan,
we can just drive off if anything comes out of the board.
kita tinggal kabur kalau ada hantu yang keluar.
Will it be that easy?
Apa akan semudah itu?
It's worth trying.
Kita bisa mencobanya.
The first time we got away was because of the truck, right?
Waktu pertama kali kita juga kabur pakai mobil ini, 'kan?
Yeah, you're right.
Ya, kau benar.
Ready to go on?
Siap bermain?
Let's get ready.
Mari bersiap.
Jord, you better roll it good this time.
Jord, lempar yang benar kali ini.
If you lose the die, I'll kill you.
Dadu hilang, mati kau.
Go ahead, Priktai.
Ayo, Pritkai.
"Wings spread wide across the midnight sky,
"Sayap membentang lebar membelah langit malam,
never bound to the earth below."
tak pernah terikat pada Bumi yang kelam.
"Should the drifting wind be felt…
Kala angin berembus membawa pertanda…
the hunt has surely begun,
perburuan tiba,
waiting to devour its prey."
siap menelan mangsa."
-Jord! -Ton!
- Jord! - Ton!
Damn!
Sial!
I'm doing my best.
Aku berusaha bertahan.
Shit, my head's burning.
Sial, kepalaku terbakar.
Priktai.
Priktai.
What the hell are you doing?!
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Ben, hit the damn thing.
Ben, injak gas.
Hang on.
Pegangan.
Hey.
Hei.
Priktai, hold on.
Priktai, pegangan.
Did you get it?
Kena?
SHARP CURVE AHEAD
TIKUNGAN TAJAM
Dad?
Ayah?
Mom?
Ibu?
Mommy.
Ibu.
Mom!
Ibu!
Mommy…
Ibu…
Mommy, wake up.
Ibu, bangun.
Mom, wake up!
Ibu, bangun!
Mommy!
Ibu!
Help!
Tolong!
Help, please…
Tolong, aku mohon…
Mom.
Ibu.
Mom!
Ibu!
Ben?
Ben?
Ben.
Ben.
Ben!
Ben!
Ben, wake up.
Ben, bangun.
Ben.
Ben.
Ben!
Ben!
Shit.
Sial.
Hey, are you all right?
Hei, kau tak apa-apa?
Go help Ben first.
Bantu Ben dulu.
Damn it, Jord.
Sialan, Jord.
Hurry.
Cepat.
Be careful, Ben.
Hati-hati, Ben.
It's all right. I can walk now.
Tidak apa-apa. Aku sudah bisa jalan.
We're almost at the finish line.
Kita hampir sampai finis.
If we cross it before Priktai's turn,
Kalau kita selesai sebelum giliran Priktai
if I roll higher than a six, the ghost won't come out.
dan aku dapat di atas enam, tak akan ada hantu.
But what if it doesn't end there?
Kalau itu tidak terjadi?
We don't have any weapons left.
Kita sudah tak punya senjata.
What about this gun?
Kalau pistol ini?
It's out of bullets.
Pelurunya habis.
Damn it!
Sialan!
Ton, the gun.
Ton, pistolnya.
Shit.
Sial.
Hey!
Hei!
Drop your weapons.
Jatuhkan senjatamu.
Hands where I can see them.
Angkat tangan.
Now.
Sekarang.
Now!
Sekarang!
Pao, they're just kids!
Pao, mereka anak-anak!
You there! What are you holding behind your back?
Kau! Apa yang kau sembunyikan?
Hands up!
Angkat tangan!
Looks like they're unarmed.
Mereka tak bersenjata.
What's that in your hand?
Apa itu di tanganmu?
Drop it.
Jatuhkan.
Drop it!
Jatuhkan!
You wanna die?
Kau mau mati?
I said, drop it.
Jatuhkan, kataku.
Drop it, or I'll shoot.
Jatuhkan atau kutembak.
Drop it, kid.
Jatuhkan, Nak.
Shit, it's a four.
Sial, empat.
Sergeant, cuff them.
Sersan, borgol mereka.
Let's go.
Ayo.
I didn't do anything!
Aku tak bersalah!
BAN NA WONG POLICE STATION
KANTOR POLISI BAN NA WONG
Come on.
Jalan.
Let's go!
Ayo!
Pao, what's with these kids?
Pao, anak-anak ini kenapa?
These kids teamed up to rob this boy's sister.
Mereka bersekongkol untuk merampok kakak anak ini.
Rotten kids already, huh? Unbelievable.
Masih kecil sudah kriminal? Sulit dipercaya.
They need to be locked up and forgotten.
Kurung dan lupakan mereka.
Take them for questioning.
Bawa mereka untuk diperiksa.
Move.
Jalan.
Damn it, my life's over.
Astaga, tamat riwayatku.
Never thought I'd end up behind bars.
Tidak kusangka bakal dipenjara.
Do you think they'll believe us?
Apa mereka akan percaya cerita kita?
I'd be crazy to believe them.
Gila kalau aku percaya.
They're definitely high.
Mereka jelas teler.
I wouldn't be surprised if they didn't.
Wajar kalau mereka tak percaya.
That sergeant…
Sersan itu…
He still thinks I stabbed someone.
Dia masih berpikir aku pelaku penikaman.
Don't be scared, kids. I'm just here to talk to Jord.
Jangan takut, Anak-Anak. Aku hanya ingin bicara dengan Jord.
How's it going, Jord?
Apa kabar, Jord?
Have you visited your brother in jail lately?
Kau sudah mengunjungi kakakmu di penjara?
I'm talking to you.
Aku berbicara denganmu.
Answer me, asshole!
Jawab aku, Bajingan!
Say something!
Katakan sesuatu!
Get up.
Bangun.
I said, get up and speak!
Bangun dan bicara, kataku!
What's your mouth for if you won't talk?
Untuk apa kau punya mulut?
Your brother's just a lowlife criminal.
Kakakmu hanya penjahat kelas teri.
Speak up.
Bicara.
Hit me back! Do it!
Pukul aku! Lakukan!
Come on, talk!
Ayo, bicara!
Where are you going? Answer me!
Mau ke mana? Jawab aku!
You scared, huh? Scared of me?
Kau takut, ya? Kau takut kepadaku?
It was an accident.
Itu kecelakaan.
But no matter what I said,
Tapi apa pun kataku,
no one believed me.
tak ada yang percaya.
Maybe it's because of how I look,
Mungkin karena penampilanku
or the fact that my brother's in jail.
atau fakta bahwa kakakku dipenjara.
People see me that way.
Orang tahunya begitu.
But sometimes I think
Kadang aku berpikir,
I might just be…
aku mungkin memang…
who they say I am.
seperti kata mereka.
No way.
Tidak.
We know you well.
Kami sangat mengenalmu.
Yeah.
Ya.
You're the biggest nerd I know.
Kau sangat culun.
Good thing those guys didn't know that.
Baguslah mereka tidak sadar.
I was bluffing, but it worked.
Itu gertakan, tapi berhasil.
Damn.
Astaga.
Yeah,
Ya,
I'm sorry I dragged you guys into this.
maaf kalian terlibat hal ini.
Now we're all screwed.
Sekarang, kita tamat.
It's okay.
Tidak apa-apa.
Actually,
Sebenarnya,
I owe you an apology too,
aku juga harus minta maaf
for not warning you about the game.
karena tak memperingatkan kalian.
It's not that I thought it was fake…
Bukan berarti aku mengira itu palsu…
but deep down, I kind of wished it was real.
tetapi dalam hati, aku berharap mereka nyata.
I hoped that ghosts would come out of the board.
Aku berharap para hantu keluar dari papan.
Because if ghosts were real…
Karena kalau hantu itu nyata…
then maybe…
mungkin…
I'd get to see my parents again.
aku bisa bertemu orang tuaku lagi.
All this time…
Selama ini…
you've been all alone.
kau selalu sendirian.
Don't worry.
Jangan cemas.
You're not alone anymore.
Kau sudah tak sendirian.
Which one of you is Ben?
Mana yang namanya Ben?
Your sister's here to pick you up.
Kakakmu menjemputmu.
Don't forget, he's got to report back.
Ingat, dia harus wajib lapor.
It's a serious case.
Ini kasus serius.
If he runs, his guardian will be held responsible.
Kalau dia kabur, walinya harus bertanggung jawab.
Ben,
Ben,
let's go home.
mari pulang.
-Ben! -Ben, don't!
- Ben! - Jangan, Ben!
Hey!
Hei!
Snap out of it!
Jaga sikap!
If you don't,
Kalau tidak,
I'll slit your sister's throat.
aku gorok leher kakakmu.
Come on.
Ayo.
-Ben! -No!
- Ben! - Jangan!
-Jord!
- Jord!
Stop it! Let go!
Berhenti! Lepas!
-Let go! -Hold them!
- Lepas! - Tahan!
What's all this?
Ada apa ini?
That's enough.
Cukup.
I'll be okay.
Tenang saja.
You think you're tough?
Merasa jagoan, ya?
Hey, there are child protection laws.
Hei, ada hukum perlindungan anak.
Is that so?
Begitu?
You can't do this!
Kau tak bisa begini!
Shit!
Sialan!
It's over for us.
Habislah kita.
We're gonna die in here.
Kita akan mati di sini.
No board, but we've got the die. We can still play, right?
Tidak ada papan, tapi ada dadu. Kita masih bisa main, 'kan?
The Four Legends never die.
Empat Legenda tak pernah mati.
Without the board, I don't know what number I need to roll.
Tanpa papan, aku tak tahu harus dapat berapa.
The board has 34 spaces,
Ada 34 petak di papan,
but we need 35 to reach finish line.
tapi butuh 35 untuk sampai finis.
We've already moved 24 spaces.
Kita sudah maju 24 petak.
So…
Berarti…
you need to roll 11 or more to win.
kau perlu angka 11 atau lebih untuk menang.
Eleven? Seriously?
Sebelas? Yang benar?
Real confusing numbers.
Angkanya membingungkan.
You've got a 2 out of 12 chance.
Peluangmu hanya dua banding 12.
That's about…
Itu sekitar
a 17% chance.
17 persen.
Shit.
Astaga.
How'd you remember that?
Kau mengingat itu?
I've been counting since the first roll.
Aku menghitungnya sejak kita bermain.
You're such a nerd.
Dasar kutu buku.
Well, at least there's still a chance.
Setidaknya, kita punya kesempatan.
You got this, Jord.
Kau bisa, Jord.
You can end the game.
Kau bisa mengakhirinya.
Hey, Pao.
Hei, Pao.
Pao.
Pao.
The board moved on its own.
Papannya bergerak sendiri.
You've been listening to them too much.
Kau terlalu mendengarkan mereka.
You're losing it.
Kau jadi gila.
Damn. Not even close.
Sial. Masih jauh.
I'll finish it myself, bro.
Biar aku yang selesaikan.
What do I need?
Aku butuh berapa?
-A 12. -God damn!
- Dua belas. - Sialan!
Pao.
Pao.
Hey.
Hei.
Suar,
Suar,
if you continue hallucinating, I swear I'll send you for a drug test.
kalau masih melantur, kau sebaiknya tes urine.
Are you insane?
Kau sudah gila, ya?
I've got a lot of work left to do.
Pekerjaanku masih banyak.
Shit! I'm even farther than Jord.
Sial! Aku bahkan lebih jauh daripada Jord.
What do you need to roll?
Kau butuh berapa?
A three.
Tiga.
Perfect.
Sempurna.
That's an easy win.
Itu mudah.
End the game.
Mari kita akhiri.
-Oh, Priktai!
- Aduh, Priktai!
Pao…
Pao…
Pao.
Pao.
I saw it.
Aku melihatnya.
Looks ancient. I don't trust it.
Ini tampak antik. Aku curiga.
Don't touch it just yet. Stuff like this…
Jangan disentuh. Barang begini…
Just tap it a bit so we can check it out, see if anything happens.
Lihat saja untuk memeriksanya andai ini bereaksi.
Is there some kind of mechanism?
Apa ada semacam alat di sini?
How did it get in there?
Bagaimana itu ada di sana?
Hey, Pao.
Hei, Pao.
Pao.
Pao.
What kind of poem is this?
Puisi macam apa ini?
Hey! Why'd you drop it?
Hei! Kenapa kau buang?
"A headless warrior from the grave
"Prajurit tak berkepala bangkit dari kuburnya,
shall bring upon you endless dread."
menebar teror abadi yang membuatmu gemetar.
"He swings his blade, slaughtering all in his path."
Dia tebas semua yang ada di depannya.
"If you become his target, best not rest."
Jika kau jadi incaran, jangan coba bersandar."
Hey.
Hei.
What the hell was that?
Apa itu tadi?
How did it go out?
Kenapa bisa mati?
Hey, who is that?
Hei, siapa di sana?
I said, who is that?
Siapa di sana?
Answer me, or I'll shoot.
Jawab atau kutembak.
Who are you?!
Siapa kau?
You got a death wish, huh?
Kau mau mati, ya?
Pao…
Pao…
What was that sound?
Suara apa itu?
Hey!
Hei!
BAN NA WONG POLICE STATION
KANTOR POLISI BAN NA WONG
Go find a place to hide.
Carilah tempat bersembunyi.
I said, get inside!
Masuk, kataku!
One,
Satu,
two…
dua…
three…
tiga…
four…
empat…
five…
lima…
six…
enam…
seven…
tujuh…
eight…
delapan…
nine…
sembilan…
ten.
sepuluh.
Shit!
Sial!
Where are you going, Ben?
Mau ke mana, Ben?
Go hide upstairs.
Bersembunyilah di atas.
Hey.
Hei.
What's that?
Apa itu tadi?
Shit.
Sial.
What the hell!
Apa ini?
Are you all right? Pao.
Kau tak apa-apa? Pao.
-Shit!
- Sial!
My gun!
Pistolku!
Holy shit!
Astaga!
Shit.
Sial.
What do we do?
Bagaimana ini?
What now?!
Bagaimana?
Shit.
Sial.
Damn it!
Sialan!
Let's go!
Ayo!
Come on, Pao!
Ayo, Pao!
The hell was that?
Apa itu tadi?
What if those kids were telling the truth?
Bagaimana kalau anak-anak itu benar?
The kids…
Anak-anak…
Fuck.
Sial.
Suar…
Suar…
Take the keys, go save them. Hurry.
Bawa kunci ini, selamatkan mereka. Cepat.
Shit, it's coming in.
Sial, ia masuk.
Pao, go!
Pergilah, Pao!
Suar, go help the kids.
Suar, bantu anak-anak.
I'll join you soon. Go.
Nanti aku menyusul. Pergi.
I'm coming for you.
Aku datang.
Come on out.
Keluar.
Sarge!
Sersan!
Sarge…
Sersan…
Damn it!
Sial!
-Hurry up, Sarge. -I'm trying. Hold on.
- Cepat, Sersan. - Aku mencoba. Sabar.
Son of a bitch!
Bajingan!
Hurry up! Get out of there!
Cepat! Keluar!
Bastard!
Kurang ajar!
Damn you!
Dasar sialan!
-Hurry, go! -Go!
- Cepat! - Ayo!
Go on, hurry!
Cepat!
-Shit! -It's locked!
- Sial! - Terkunci!
Move!
Minggir!
-Sarge! -Go!
- Sersan! - Pergi!
Sarge!
Sersan!
-Hurry, go!
- Cepat!
-Shit, it's coming! -Sarge!
- Sial, ia datang! - Sersan!
Go on, wait for Sarge!
Ayo, tunggu Sersan!
-Go!
- Pergi!
It's coming!
Ia datang!
Which one, Sarge?
Yang mana, Sersan?
Sarge!
Sersan!
Shit.
Sial.
-Sarge! -Sarge, stay with us.
- Sersan! - Sersan, sadarlah.
Jord.
Jord.
Get out of here.
Pergi dari sini.
Stay strong, Sarge.
Bertahanlah, Sersan.
Damn it.
Sial.
I'll get you, you bastard.
Habislah kau, kurang ajar!
Hey, kid…
Hei, Nak…
You're still young.
Kau masih kecil.
Don't play with guns.
Jangan main senapan.
Take your bike keys back…
Ambil kunci motormu…
and get your friends out of here.
dan bawa pergi teman-temanmu.
Yes, sir.
Baik, Pak.
Go.
Pergi.
Jord, we need to go.
Jord, kita harus pergi.
Jord.
Jord.
Go.
Pergi.
Jord, go.
Ayo, Jord.
-Jord. -Go!
- Jord. - Pergi!
-Jord! -Sarge!
- Jord! - Sersan!
We need to go!
Kita harus pergi!
You want my head?
Kau ingin kepalaku?
Come and get it.
Coba ambil.
Ben, come be with Mommy, sweetie.
Ben, ikut Ibu, Sayang.
The three of us can be together.
Kita bertiga bisa bersama.
You're such a liar.
Dasar pembohong.
You cheated, didn't you?
Kau curang, 'kan?
I made this game to win every round.
Aku buat ini agar aku selalu menang.
You beat me every time. Something's off.
Tapi kau selalu mengalahkanku. Aneh.
Just admit it, you cheated.
Mengaku saja, kau curang.
That's bullshit. I didn't cheat.
Omong kosong. Aku tidak curang.
Tell me, did you cheat or not?
Jawab, kau curang atau tidak?
I didn't.
Tidak.
Really?
Benarkah?
Wanna know something?
Kau mau tahu rahasia?
What?
Apa?
I lied. I was joking.
Aku bohong. Bercanda.
You little shit. I'm gonna kick your ass.
Kurang ajar. Kuhajar kau.
BEN - TON - JORD TREASURE HUNTERS
BEN, TON, JORD PEMBURU HARTA KARUN
Ben!
Ben!
Ben, man! Ben!
Ben, Temanku! Ben!
Ben?
Ben?
Ben! Ben?
Ben!
Hey, Ben.
Hei, Ben.
It's your turn now.
Ini giliranmu.
Roll the die.
Lempar dadunya.
Forget it.
Lupakan saja.
My mom and sister are waiting for me.
Ibu dan kakakku sudah menunggu.
But, Ben…
Tapi Ben…
we're about to win, man.
kita hampir menang.
Ben!
Ben!
-Ben!
- Ben!
-I've got her.
- Aku menahannya.
-It's your turn, Ben. -Roll the die!
- Giliranmu, Ben. - Lempar dadunya!
Ben, it's your turn to roll!
Ben, giliranmu melempar dadu!
Hold her back!
Tahan dia!
Ton, grab her!
Ton, pegang dia!
Bell, stop it!
Bell, berhenti!
-Jord, grab her! -I got her.
- Jord, pegang dia! - Sudah.
-Damn it! -Ben!
- Sial! - Ben!
-Lock it!
- Kunci!
Find something to lock it!
Cari sesuatu untuk mengganjal.
Go on! Go!
Ayo! Cepat!
-Go! -Just go!
- Ayo! - Lakukan!
-Get the die! -Go find the die!
- Ambil dadunya! - Cari dadunya!
Ton, keep it closed. We're about to win.
Ton, tahan. Kita hampir menang.
Grab that chair.
Ambil kursi itu.
Damn it, Jord, hurry!
Sial, Jord, cepat!
Where's the die?
Di mana dadunya?
Did you find it?
Kau menemukannya?
Not yet. Help me look for it.
Belum. Bantu aku mencarinya.
Why is it so hard to find?
Kenapa sulit ditemukan?
Ben.
Ben.
Knife.
Pisau.
Found it.
Aku menemukannya.
Priktai?
Priktai?
Mom.
Ibu.
How are you? Are you okay, dear?
Apa kabar, Sayang? Kau baik-baik saja?
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
If I hadn't wanted to meet my friend that day…
Andai aku tak memaksa untuk bertemu temanku hari itu…
this wouldn't have happened.
ini tak akan terjadi.
Everyone died because of me.
Semua orang mati karena aku.
I miss you both so much.
Aku sangat merindukan kalian.
Don't cry, my baby.
Jangan menangis, Sayang.
We'll be together now.
Kini kita akan bersama.
Priktai…
Priktai…
Don't give in, Priktai.
Jangan menyerah, Priktai.
Don't do it, Priktai.
Jangan, Priktai.
Don't you dare give up yet.
Jangan menyerah.
Fight it.
Lawan.
I really can't be with you right now.
Aku tak bisa bersama kalian sekarang.
Why not?
Kenapa?
My friends are waiting for me.
Teman-temanku menunggu.
Priktai…
Priktai…
You're not my parents!
Kalian bukan orang tuaku!
You…
Kau…
You wretched kid.
Anak sialan.
Ben, the die…
Ben, dadunya…
You dare?
Kau berani?
Make your choice then.
Kalau begitu, pilih.
No!
Jangan!
You think I don't know
Kau pikir aku tak tahu…
that brats like you…
bocah sepertimu…
love to play tricks.
suka bermain curang.
Then your sister's body
Tubuh kakakmu
will be mine.
akan jadi milikku.
You're that desperate to save her?
Kau begitu ingin menyelamatkannya, ya?
You want to know how much she hates you?
Kau ingin tahu seberapa dia membencimu?
I don't know how much she hates me…
Entah seberapa dia membenciku…
but I do know how much I love her.
tapi aku sangat menyayanginya.
And another thing…
Satu hal lagi…
stay the hell out of my family's business.
jangan ikut campur urusan keluargaku.
Six o'clock.
Pukul 06.00.
-Six o'clock.
- Pukul 06.00.
Yes!
Bagus!
We made it.
Kita berhasil.
Does it hurt?
Apa sakit?
Priktai.
Priktai.
As the leader of the Four Legends,
Sebagai ketua Empat Legenda,
welcome aboard.
selamat datang.
Yeah. Thanks, Ton.
Ya. Terima kasih, Ton.
Yo, you just got in, yet you're already acting chummy?
Baru bergabung sudah sok akrab, ya?
Finally, we're a gang of four now.
Akhirnya, kita berempat sekarang.
Who said four?
Kata siapa empat?
There's five now.
Ada lima sekarang.
Got it, Ton?
Paham, Ton?
Wait a minute.
Tunggu.
How am I gonna explain this mess to my mom?
Bagaimana aku menjelaskan kekacauan ini kepada ibuku?
You can tell her
Katakan kepadanya
that we were playing a board game.
kalau kita main permainan papan.
Subtitle translation by: Thanatcha Saksiamkul
Terjemahan subtitle oleh Nola Mardiana